

Antonio Martins

Dispensing Optician /Technician Optician Green Belt Front-end developer

Experienced Licensed Optician with over 10 years of experience. Dedicated Optical professional with history of meeting company goals utilizing consistent and organized practices.

Excited to be at the deployment phase of my new career as a web developer. I am ambitious, adventurous, assiduous, animated and perseverant.



antonio.fmartins@icloud.com



(+351) 934 659 502

Porto, Portugal



github.com/antonio-fmartins/

Visit my portfolio at the link below dev.antoniomartins.vercel.app



WORK EXPERIENCE

Optician

Oculos para Todos, Porto, Portugal

2023-Present

Obtain specifications for eyeglasses or contact lenses from a prescription or by analyzing the client's eyeglasses or contact lenses, /Advice clients on eyeglasses selection by informing them of different products such as lens materials, frames, tints and anti-reflection coating, /Assembly and Adjustment finished eyeglasses to fit cliente.

Optician - Store Manager

Optica Ativa, Florianopolis, Brazil

2022-2022 (9 months)

Manage staff and assign duties, /Stock Management, /Obtain specifications for eyeglasses or contact lenses from a prescription or by analyzing the client's eyeglasses or contact lenses, /Advice clients on eyeglasses selection by informing them of different products such as lens materials, frames, tints and anti-reflection coating, /Assembly and Adjustment finished eyeglasses to fit cliente.

Quality Process Manager and Glazing Lab Manager

Rodenstock Italia S.p.A, Milano, Italy

2019-2022

Continuously collect and explore all information about the processes and how it works, /Developing KPI for production monitoring (waste time, scraps, delivery time, productivity), /Working closely with team members to provide effective solutions to support business and quality objectives, /Production planning and control with emphasis on production data analysis, /Production Team Management (absences, shifts, admissions, layoffs, holidays...), /Member team responsible for projects, with the aim of cost reduction and productivity improvement.

Edging-Glazing Lab and Warehouse Manager

OptoVision, Milano, Italy

2018-2019

Manage reporting, monitoring, resources and laboratory personnel, / Work closely with team members to provide effective solutions to support business and quality objectives, / Facilitate effective communication between internal departments by trending and reporting data, / Establish and improve procedures and processes, addressing issues and risks, / Production Manager (training, schedules, holiday, hiring...), / Keep corporate departments and customers updated on critical shipments, / MeiSystem Operations and Maintenance.

Optician - Store Manager

Opticenter, Porto, PT

2016-2018

Manage staff and assign duties, /Stock Management, /Obtain specifications for eyeglasses or contact lenses from a prescription or by analyzing the client's eyeglasses or contact lenses, /Advice clients on eyeglasses selection by informing them of different products such as lens materials, frames, tints and anti-reflection coating, /Assembly and Adjustment finished eyeglasses to fit cliente.

Optician/Technician Lab - Manager

Shamir Optical Portugal, Porto, PT

2012-2016

Technician Optical Lab, /Machine Operator CNC – MeiSytem, /Operated lensometers to orient and mark uncut lenses for eyeglasses, /Quality Control, /Assembly of eyeglasses, /Coordinate team to achieve goals.



CONFERENCES & COURSES

The Complete Oracle SQL Bootcamp (2023-present)

Udemy

Course Complet Git & GitHub ReactJS (Curso Git & GitHub Completo)

Danki Code (Online Course)

Credencial: https://cursos.dankicode.com/api/certificados/1c85f815-5983-4e2f-8a88-2741b2e30b20

Course ReactJS (Curso ReactJS)

Danki Code (Online Course)

Credential: https://cursos.dankicode.com/api/certificados/99d3c20a-da43-42c0-af9b-c0d72ce75bc3

Course Complet JavaScrict (Curso JavaScript Completo)

Danki Code (Online Course)

Course Complet Front-end 2.0 (Curso Front-end Completo 2.0)

Danki Code (Online Course)

Credential: https://cursos.dankicode.com/api/certificados/8aa6e22f-f162-450a-a055-69ccc1f32ba1

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

FM2S Educação e Consultoria – Credential ID: 117833 – No expiration date

Credential: https://ead.fm2s.com.br/certificado/117833

Flowchart, SIPOC and Process Map

FM2S Educacao e Consultoria – Credential ID: 192769 – No expiration date Credential: https://ead.fm2s.com.br/certificado/192769/

OKR – Objectives and Key Results

FM2S Educação e Consultoria – Credential ID: 196824 – No expiration date Credential: https://ead.fm2s.com.br/certificado/196824/





EDUCATION

Dispensing Optician -Certification Lv.4 - Opticianry

2008-201



INTERESTS



Machine Learning



Robotics



Travel